Finding aid for the Barbara Aziz broadcasts collection
Bentley Historical Library
- News broadcasts, 1990-2005
  - Behind the News, 1991-2002
    - December 22, 1992, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:35); (Analysis, Somalia, Palestine, Lebanon. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Ibish, Hussein; Tony Benn UK parliamentarian. Topics: Analysis, Somalia, Palestine, Lebanon.)
    - December 31, 1992, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:27:16); (Hamid sumarizes human rights ad economic conditions in Sudan; Makawi comments on Israeli deportation of 415 Palestinians to Lebanon and UN resolution, with further comment by Ibish. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Hamid, Mohammed Bashir, Washington Wilson Center; Ibsih, Hussein; Makawi, Khalil UN Lebanon Ambassador; Ibish, Hussein, Amherst journalist. Topics: Sudan, Lebanon.)
    - January 7, 1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:24:02); (Commentary on US policy in Iraq. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Renfrew, Nita, Journalist, NY. Topics: Iraq.)
    - January 11, 1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:36); (Discussion of air embargo on Iraq and rwlations with neighboring Arab states. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Renfrew, Nita, Journalist, NY. Topics: Iraq, Sanctions.)
    - March 12, 1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:04); (Warren discusses media interpretations after bombing at NYC World Trade Center and growing anti-Muslim publications; Aziz reviews books on Arab and Muslim women, Saadawi comments on growth of international women's movement. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz, segment starts at -46 min. Interviewees/Guests: Warren, Tarif, NY-based attorney; Saadawi, Nawal, author and women's solidarity leader. Topics: civil rights, media, Arab/Muslim women.)
    - August 1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:01:19); (Lebanon peace talks commentaries. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Makawi, Khalil, Lebanon UN Ambassador; Maksoud, Clovis, Prof American U Washington; Ibish, H. Amherst. Topics: Lebanon, US policy, Middle East.)
    - March 15, 1994, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:29:38); (Islam and Black Nationalism, Colonialism, Israeli Policy. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Samad, Asha, NY Prof of Anthropology: Ibish, Hussein, U. Amherst. Topics: African History, Palestine.)
    - October 12, 1994, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:20:15); (Middle East Regional Policy, Kuwait Iraq. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Samori Marksman. Interviewees/Guests: Hussein Ibish. Topics: Political History.)
    - May 29, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:24:16); (Pre recorded interviews, listener calls (Iraq). Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Iraq, Kerbala Hospital Doctors. Topics: Iraq Medical Reports.)
    - May - June 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:04:00); (Iraq medical conditions, sanctions. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Iraqi Doctors, BN Aziz' reports. Topics: Iraq, sanctions.)
    - June 30, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:00); (Turkey and Syria commentaries. Hosts: BNAziz. Interviewees/Guests: Ali Tmsen; Ibish, Hussein. Topics: Turkey, Syria, Middle East policy.)
    - July 5, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:03:29); (Iraq medical conditions; Egypt-Sudan political relations, image of Arab Americans. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Dr.Obeid, Iraq Kerbala hospital staff; Dr. Mohammed B Hamid, Sudanese scholar; Jabara, Abdeen, US civil rights attorney. Topics: commentary.)
    - July 12, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:36:15); (Iraq political analysis. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Nita Renfrew, Nita; Iraq Foreign Minister Al-Sahaf, Moh S.. Topics: Political Comment.)
    - July 19, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:07:35); (Palestine, Syria comment; Gaza book review with author. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Ibish, Hussein, U. Amherst; author, editor Doughty, Dick. Topics: middle east.)
    - August 16, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:48:40); (Lebanon, Hizbollah, Iraq political analysis. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Ibish, Hussein. Topics: Commentary, History.)
    - August 23, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:34:39); (Desutter, on "Builders for Peace" in Gaza and the West Bank; Carroll critically comments on US policies in Middle East with weapons sales. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Joseph Desutter, of Builders for Peace, Fmr Admiral Eugen Carroll. Topics: Palestine, Iraq, US policies in Iraq, Jordan, Middle East.)
    - August 30, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:03:44); (Beijing Women's conference report, comment Bosnia, Iraq. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Madre Representative;. Topics: Conference Report.)
    - September 6, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:34:13); (Flanders direct live in Beijing on features and issues of conference underway, NJ Women's organizers speak on their work combating violence. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based journalist, feminist Laura Flanders, Combating Racism Task Force, NJ. Topics: women, 4th UN Int'l Conference on Women, Beijing, violence, US civil rights.)
    - November 6, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:42:00); (Ibish review inglorious history of slain Israeli leader Rabin and future prospects for peace process. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Ibish, Hussein, Analyst Amherst;. Topics: Israel.)
    - February 25, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:28); (Comment on Hebron Palestine agreement. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Samara, Adel; Ramallah, Palestine based writer, analyst. Topics: Middle east policy.)
    - April 14, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:27:50); (Samara comments on Palestinian police action and Israeli policy, Ibish comment on US policy. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Dr. Adel Samara, Ramallah-based Palestine writer analyst, Hussein Ibish, Amherst, MASS. Topics: Middle East policy.)
    - May 20, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:21:29); (Yemen political analysis. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Borrows, B Professor. Topics: Middle East Policy.)
    - August 16, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:17:26); (Oslo Peace Accord comment. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Samara, Adel, Author, critic, Ramallah. Topics: Palestine, Israel, Middle East Policy.)
    - November 20, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:22:54); (Iraq economy under sanctions. Hosts: Henwood, Doug. Interviewees/Guests: BN Aziz, journalist, ME correspondent. Topics: Middle East.)
    - December 9, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:31:00); (Comment on US policy and Iran. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Andrew Killigore, former US ambassador; Hiro Dilip London based Journalist. Topics: OIC (Organization of Islamic States) Islamic Summit conference.)
    - January 5, 1998, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:59); (Hamdoon comments on US and UN embargo policies against Iraq, possibilities for future. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Nizar Hamdoon Iraq Ambassador to UN. Topics: Iraq, sanctions, US policies.)
    - February 5, 1998, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:30:18); (Comment on Jordanian economy and regional politics. Hosts: Henwood, Doug. Interviewees/Guests: BN Aziz, Ibish, H. Topics: Middle East, Jordan, economy.)
    - 2000, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:31:40); (Discussing Palestinian right of return. Hosts: BNAziz. Interviewees/Guests: Boyle, Francis, U Illinois, Professor. Topics: Palestine.)
    - April 16, 2000, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:34); (Palestine policy, human rights. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Usher, Graham, Jerusalem based journalist; Mustafa, Hanan American Palestinian. Topics: Middle East.)
    - September 5, 2000, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:28:36); (Al-Najjar reports on his reseacrh work in the US and detention by US authorities and ongoing hearings. Hosts: Mealy, Rosemary; Aziz, BN. Interviewees/Guests: al-Najjar, Mazin, political prisoner; Hochenstein, Joe, Civil rights attorney. Topics: civil rights, US Muslims.)
    - October 2, 2000, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:28); (Jaradat reports on conditions in West Bank, Aruri comments on media coverage of Palestinan deaths. Hosts: Mealy, Rosemary. Interviewees/Guests: Aziz, BN, Journalist; Jaradat, Mohammed, West Bank Bethleham community leader, Aruri, Nasir Prof Dartmouth. Topics: Palestine, Middle East Policy.)
    - October 8, 2000, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:22:44); (Iraq--sanctions and oil production past policy. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Hiro, Dilip London based journalist, author. Topics: Middle East policy.)
    - January 2, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:29:40); (Comment on Palestine, Israel, Middle East Policy, featuring Rashid Khalidi. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Khalidi, Rashid, Professor, Columbia U. New York. Topics: Palestine, Israel, Middle East Policy.)
    - January 9, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:08:01); (Episode on Iraq, Palestine, and Iraq, featuring Dilip Hiro, Margarita Papandreou, and Sara Flounders)
    - January 16, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:39); (Report on Iraq and effects of depleted uranium on humans and environment. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Arbuthnot, Felicity, London based Journalist, Bossy, Bob, Voices in the Wilderness Member. Topics: Iraq sanctions, depleted uranium.)
    - March 6, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:27); (Episode on Iraq, Israel, North Africa, and Palestine, featuring Peter Lennon, Dilip Hiro, Laila Atshan, and Nahid Al-Tamini)
    - March 13, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:36); (Episode on Britain's Terrorism Act and American secret evidence, featuring Sabah Al-Mukhtar and Hilary Han)
    - March 27, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:00); (Episode on Palestinian prisoners and the Taliban, featuring Khalida Jarrar and Enver Masud)
    - April 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:13); (Khan comment on Pakistan society; AsalI on US-Israeli policy. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Afzal-Khan, Fawzia, Prof Montclair New Jersey; Asali, Ziad Washington DC Community Leader. Topics: Pakistan, Middle East policy.)
    - April 24, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:04:39); (Aziz Comment on Nepal labor issues; Chosodofsky reports on Summit of Americas in Quebec. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Michael Chossodofsky, Canadian Economist, professor. Topics: Nepal, Economic Summit.)
    - June 12, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:05:15); (Tribute to Palestinian-American Prof Ibrahim Abu Lughod, comment on massacre of Nepal royal family. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Maksoud, Clovis, Prof American U Washington; Hagopian, Elaine Boston Prof; Gerner, Deborah Professor; Nepali Scholars Dahal, DiliRam, Adikari, Gauri. Topics: Ibrahim Abu Lughod, Nepal.)
    - June 26, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:15); (Cannon reports on European delegation to Iraq; Dilip Hiro comments on new UN sanctions on Iraq. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Cannon, Lauren, Voices in the Wilderness delegation; Hiro, Dilip, Author, London based Journalist. Topics: Iraq, Sanctions.)
    - July 3, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:03:57); (Sami al-Arian comments on walkout of Muslims from US govt meeting; comment on Macedonia. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Sami Al-Arian, U. Florida Prof; Michel Chossodofsky, Prof U Ottawa, Canada. Topics: Civil Rights of Muslim Americans, Macedonia.)
    - July 10, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:09); (Comment on politicization on International Hague courts. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Clark, Ramsey, Civil Rights Attorney NYC, former US Attorney General. Topics: Civil Rights, UN court.)
    - July 17, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:18); (Comment on misinformation regarding Iraq military and sanctions; comment on anti-muslim riots in the UK. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Weiss, Jeff AFSC rep; Ali, Etisham, UK based Journalist. Topics: Iraq sanctions, Muslim civil rights.)
    - August 7, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:26); (Comment on US-UN sanctions policy. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Kelly Kathy, Head of Voices in the Wilderness; Denis Halliday, former UN officer in Iraq. Topics: Iraq, US policy, Middle East, Sanctions.)
    - September 4, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:48:10); (Reports on various civil rights issues covered at Durban, and Palestinian Resolution; Zogby talks about NY Arabs and state elections. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Al-Fazad, Arjan, Jerusalem resident; Zogby, J. director of AAI (Arab American Insitute), Washington. Topics: Durban, S. A. Youth Summit; civil rights; US election.)
    - September 25, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:25); (Al-Arian reports on difficulties of US Muslims; Hiro analyses basis of Muslim people abroad disaffection with US policies and views of Iran; Flounders announces anti-war actions across the USA. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Al-Arian, Sami; prof. Florida based; Hiro, Dilip, London-based author; Flounders, Sara, IAC, NY. Topics: civil rights, US Muslims; Middle East.)
    - October 2, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:14); (Poem; Ashan reports on living in the West Bank under Israeli occupation and road closures; Kaku reviews imperial and interests in Middle East after WWI and concept of blowback. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Hamad, Suheir, Poet; Atshan Laila, West Bank based phychologist; Kaku, Michio, CUNY, NY-based professor of Physics. Topics: Palestine, Middle East Policy.)
    - October 16, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:39); (Gage reviews campaign against secret evidence; status of anti-teror bill in Congress; Nassar testifies regarding his arrest and jailing; discussion of how Muslims can protect themselves. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Stewart, Lynne,civil rights attorney, c; Ahmed, Nassar, former political prisoner, Gage, Kit (NCPPF) Washington;. Topics: US Civil Rights, Anti-terror Bill, campaign against secret evidence.)
    - December 25, 2001, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:49:01); (Christmas special, with music)
    - January 1, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:13); (Report on Bonn, Germany Conference on Afghanistan; current political developments. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Nawa, Fariba, Journalist US. Topics: Afghanistan.)
    - January 8, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:56); (Discussion of the case of Mazin Al-Najjar and civil rights of Muslims in the US. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Gage,Kit, Coordinator National Coalition to Protect Political Freedom, Washington. Topics: Civil Rights in USA.)
    - January 15, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:04:45); (Demonstrations to support US Muslims, report of wrong dismissal of Al-Arian on political grounds. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Saed, Zohra, Afghan-American Brooklyn NY student, poet; Sami Al-Arian U. Florida Professor. Topics: Civil Rights in USA, Afghanistan, literature.)
    - January 22, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:30:49); (Boyle comments on US detention of prisoners in Afghanistan and questions the authority of the Patriot Act. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Ali, Kazim, Poet; Boyle, Frances, U.Illinois Prof. Topics: Poetry reading, Afghanistan, Patriot Act.)
    - January 29, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:05:14); (Aziz comment on Afghan destruction of Bamyan statues; Rankamanus on persecution of Mindanao Muslims; Flounders announces demonstrations and war. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Rankamanus, Potri; Flounders, Sara. Topics: Afghanistan, Philippines, Mindanao.)
    - February 26, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:49:26); (Comment regarding reparations by Iraq to other countries, UN commission for reparations. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Kane, Suzy US author. Topics: Iraq, Sanctions.)
    - March 5, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:06:10); (Episode on Palestine, Israel, and hate crimes on Arab and Muslim American citizens, featuring Graham Usher and Omar Mohammedi)
    - March 12, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:47); (Recorded statement by Kofi Anan on deaths of West Bank Palestinians in conflict with Israel, followed by comment by Hansen on possibilities for peace; Mahmoud reports on conditions of Muslim detainees in the US. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Anan, Kofi UN Gen Secretary; Hansen M, UK based journalist; Mahmoud Magdy, NJ based activist. Topics: Middle East, Palestine, Civil Rights, US Muslims.)
    - March 26, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:04); (Palestinian legal and political rights, Arab-Americans Detained in NY-NJ. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Professor Frances Boyle, U. Illinois, Urbana; Amira Habibi Brown, NYC Arab American community center director. Topics: Palestine, US civil rights, Arab-Americans.)
    - April 2, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:05:27); (Comment on Nepal Maoist movement; author Ron David on Israeli Policy regarding Palestinians. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Nepali commentator; Author Ron David. Topics: Middle East, Palestine, Nepal.)
    - April 9, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:01:15); (Comment on US policy towards Israel, Ali discusses "The Clash of Fundamentalisms". Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Clovis Maksoud, Prof American U. Washington; Author Tariq Ali London. Topics: Israeli Policy, Middle East History, US Policy.)
    - circa May 7, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:02:12); (Episode on the Pacifica Network)
    - May 28, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:05:08); (Episode on Iraq, American secret evidence, Israel, and Palestine, featuring Nermin al-Mufti, Kit Gage, Graham Usher)
    - June 4, 2002, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:24); (Gage comments on US Muslim rights, anti-war announcements, developments in Nepal's democracy movement. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz, Habatfa, N.. Interviewees/Guests: Gage,Kit, Coordinator National Coalition to Protect Political Freedom, Washington, Sharma M. Nepal Ambassador. Topics: Civil Rights, US Muslims, Nepal.)
  - Other reports and programs
    - 1991, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:36:03); (Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC) and WBAI news reports)
    - circa March 8, 1996, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:44:31); (Celebrating Arab American women with Naomi Shihab Nye and Mohja Kahf. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Naomi Shihab Nye, poet, Mohja Kahf, poet. Topics: poetry, women, Arab American.)
    - Labbrish, circa 1992-1993
      - January 16, 1992, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:33); (Interviews with Nizar Hamdoon, Nita Renfrew, Hussein Ibish)
      - circa December 19, 1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:43); (Habte Selassie interviews Barbara Nimri Aziz)
    - The Morning Show and Wake Up Call, 1993-1997
      - March 12, 1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:35:21); (Interviews with Nita Renfrew and Inea Bushnaq)
      - circa October - November 1994, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:33:12); (Segments on Iraq, featuring Hussein Ibish and Amy Goodman. Also includes a Behind the News segment)
      - May 3, 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:23:51); (Interview with Barbara Nimri Aziz on Syria)
      - November 1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:09:40); (Interview on Islamic education)
      - 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:21:46); (Conversation with Barbara Nimri Aziz and interview with Yvonne Yazbeck Haddad)
      - November 20, 1997, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:18:13); (Interview with Barbara Nimri Aziz on Iraq's sanctions and medical consequences)
    - Somalia Watch, 1992
      - December 24, 1992, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:12:22); (Interview with Asha Samad)
      - December 30, 1992, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:26:04); (Report on US military intervention, humanitarian conditions, Aziz reports on Red Cross aid in Somalia. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: David Funkhauser, AFSC Africa Desk coordinator. Topics: Somalia, US policy and military.)
    - TalkBack episodes, Pacifica Network News reports, and related materials, 1990-2005
      - 1990-1999, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:26:03); (Excerpts of samples of Aziz reports from Middle East regarding conditions, sanctions, war, policies, literature. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: BN Aziz, producer, reporter. Topics: Palestine, Iraq, sanctions, post-1991 war economic and cultural conditions in Iraq.)
      - 1991, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:10); (From Jordan, Aziz reports on deteriorating living conditions for Palestinians, report on conditions and Iraqi political views; health and economic conditions after 1991 war against Iraq. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Aziz correspondent reports from Iraq, Palestine, Jordan. Topics: Palestine, Iraq, sanctions, post-1991 war econmic and cultural conditions in Iraq.)
      - 1991, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:20:51); (Kharahan discusses the contemporary film "Not Without My Daughter" and stereotypes of Islam and Iran. Hosts: Paul Wunder. Interviewees/Guests: BN Aziz and H. Kharahan NY resident. Topics: Iran, film, women.)
      - 1991, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:51:25); (Comments and reports made to programs Undercurrents, WBAI news, Pacifica News. Hosts: various. Interviewees/Guests: summary of 1991 overseas reports by BNAziz. Topics: Middle East, US policy, Sryia.)
      - 1991-1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:06:33); (Aziz in Jordan reports on Syria's release of more than 1000 Palestinian prisoners; Aziz in Baghdad report on health conditions and crisis in hospitals; Report on Iraqi Kurdish area and US troops in N Iraq Interviewees/Guests: Aziz report from Jordan and Baghdad. Topics: Syria, Middle East, Prisoners, Palestine, Iraq, sanctions.)
      - April 6, 1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:52); (Bosnia, US Muslims, discrimination, human rights. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: BN Aziz journalist, producer, announcements. Topics: Bosnia, US Muslims, discrimination, human rights.)
      - April 20, 1993, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:06); (Discussion of the need for health care reform in the US, comparisons with other systems, and listener comments. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: BN Aziz, journalist, producer, hosting; guest Meredith Coladner of "HealthCareWeve GottoHaveIt". Topics: US health conditions, crisis.)
      - November 24, 1994, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:38:29); (Host and guests address growing difficulties facing Muslims in the US, prejudice, attacks, bullying. Hosts: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: BN Aziz, hosting special production of "TalkBack", guests Shakir Al-Sayed, Sheik Obeid, Anis Abdul Fattah, Prof. Nasir Aruri, US poet Mohja Kahf. Topics: Islam, US Muslims, civil rights .)
      - circa 1994-1995, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:22:30); (Jabrā Ibrāhīm Jabrā and Palestine news reports)